TOMMASO INNOCENTI

+1 857-928-9979 | innocenti.t@northeastern.edu | linkedin.com/in/innotommy| github.com/innotommy https://innotommy.com/ Boston (MA)

Research Overview

My research focuses on Security and Privacy to increase the security of general users. My works reflect my passion and tenacity to investigate complex security problems. With my research, I increased the security of the Best Current Practice of OAuth and the OpenID protocol. Various topics in Web Security attract my interest, but the current focal point of my research is Web Authentication.

EDUCATION

Sep. 2018 – (Expected Nov. 2024) Ph.D. Computer Science | Cybersecurity Northeastern University | GPA: 4.0/4.0 Boston, USA Master in Computer Science and Engineering Sep. 2014 – May 2018 Politecnico di Milano | Grade: 101/110 Milano, Italy **Erasmus Experience** Sep. 2015 – Feb. 2016 Universidad Complutense de Madrid (UCM) Madrid, Spain

WORK EXPERIENCE

Amazon Jun. 2024 – Aug. 2024

Amazon Web Services | AWS security engineer

NewYork, USA

• Evaluated current state of the art for domain generation algorithm (DGA) and DNS data-exfiltration identification against AWS detection system

LEADERs Program Spring 2020 – (ongoing)

Gordon Institute of Engineering Leadership | Northeastern University

Boston, USA

· Applied experiential learning initiative that integrates leadership and professional-skills within a research project

Research Assistant Apr. 2018 – Sep. 2018

Northeastern University

Boston, USA

- Managed a research topic in a team environment
- Performed cutting edge security research

Master Thesis at SecLab Nov. 2016 – June 2017

Less is more (Secure): automated reduction of the attack surface in modern Browser

Boston, USA

- Investigated the Browser functionalities as potential attack surface
- Instrumented the Browser functionalities to define the minimal set of required functionality
- Generated a model able to reduce the Attack surface and increase the browser performance

PROJECTS AND RESEARCH

"Only as Strong as the Weakest Link": On the Security of Brokered Single Sign-On on the Web Spring 2024 Tommaso Innocenti, Louis Jannett, Christian Mainka, Vladislav Mladenov, Engin Kirda San Francisco, CA IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy '25 | (A.R. 106/739 = 14.3%)

OAuth 2.0 Redirect URI Validation Falls Short, Literally

Fall 2023

Tommaso Innocenti, Matteo Golinelli, Ali Mirheidari, Kaan Onarlioglu, Bruno Crispo, Engin Kirda Austin, TX $ACSAC'23 \mid (A.R. 104/497 = 20.9\%)$

FRAMESHIFTER: Security Implications of HTTP/2-to-HTTP/1 Conversion Anomalies

Sum 2022

Bahruz Jabiyev, Steven Sprecher, Anthony Gavazzi, Tommaso Innocenti, Kaan Onarlioglu, Engin Kirda USENIX'22 | (A.R. 392/2535 = 15.4%)

Boston, MA

You've Got (a Reset) Mail: A Security Analysis of Email-Based Password Reset Procedures

Sum 2021

Tommaso Innocenti, Ali Mirheidari, Amin Kharraz, Bruno Crispo, Engin Kirda

Virtual

DIMVA'21 | (A.R. 16/66 = 28.7%)

CONFERENCES AND PRESENTATIONS

March 2024 **OWASP Italy Meetup** OAuth 2.0 Redirect URI Validation Falls Short, Literally Virtual **OWASP Boston Chapter December meetup** December 2023 OAuth 2.0 Redirect URI Validation Falls Short, Literally Boston, Massachusetts Annual Computer Security Applications Conference (ACSAC)'23 December 2023 OAuth 2.0 Redirect URI Validation Falls Short, Literally Austin, Texas OAuth Security Workshop (OSW)'23 August 2023 OAuth 2.0 Redirect URI Validation Falls Short, Literally Royal Holloway University, London Federal Trade Commission (FTC) invited talk October 2021 You've Got (a Reset) Mail: A Security Analysis of Email-Based Password Reset Procedures Virtual Detection of Intrusions and Malware & Vulnerability Assessment (DIMVA)'21 July 2021 Virtual You've Got (a Reset) Mail: A Security Analysis of Email-Based Password Reset Procedures PROFESSIONAL SERVICES/NETWORK Co-Chair Security Interest Group (SING) - Invited Expert July 2024 World Wide Web Consortium (W3C) **OpenID** foundation October 2023 Conformance-suite **IETF OAuth Working Group** October 2023 OAuth 2.0 Security Best Current Practice Conference on Computer and Communications Security (CCS)'23 November 2022 Sub-reviewer Copenhagen, Denmark USENIX'23 August 2022 Anaheim, California Sub-reviewer SELECTED ACHIEVEMENT / GRANTS Northeastern University Dissertation Completion Fellowships August 2024 PhD network Boston, Massachusetts Third place at Tracer FIRE (Forensic Incident Response Exercise) December 2023 Capture The Flag | Workshop ACSAC '23 Austin, Texas Annual Computer Security Applications Conference ACSAC '23 December 2023 OAuth 2.0 Redirect URI Validation Falls Short, Literally | Travel grant Austin, Texas Connect2id security fix September 2023 OAuth 2.0 Redirect URI Validation Falls Short, Literally Bulgaria August 2023 OAuth Security Workshop (OSW)'23 OAuth 2.0 Redirect URI Validation Falls Short, Literally | Student scholarship London, United Kingdom GO Language | CVE-2022-27664 September 2022

Google, Mountain View

Wakefield, Massachusetts

Complutense University of Madrid

Sep. 2015 Feb. 2016

August 2022

SKILLS

Erasmus+

Exchange program

Languages: English C1 (TOEFL score:100/120), Spanish A1, Italian (mother tongue)

FRAMESHIFTER: Security Implications of HTTP/2-to-HTTP/1 Conversion Anomalies

FRAMESHIFTER: Security Implications of HTTP/2-to-HTTP/1 Conversion Anomalies

Programming: C, Java, C++, Python, SQL, HTML, Node.js, Puppeteer, JavaScript, Docker, Git

Document Creation: Microsoft Office Suite, LaTex

Apache Traffic Server | CVE-2022-31780